Australia's untold history
High Ground is a thriller, action, drama film directed by Stephen Johnson.
In a remote corner of the wild country, a bloody war rages.
Travis is a bounty hunter with one last hope of redemption.
Gutjuk is a young Indigenous man trying to save the last of his family.
Together they embark on a manhunt, which unravels a secret
that ultimately pits them against each other.
Travis, played by Simon Baker.
Gutjuk, played by Jacob Junior Nayinggul.
Moran, played by Jack Thompson.
Ambrose, played by Callan Mulvey.
Claire, played by Caren Pistorius.
Grandfather Dharrpa, played by Witiyana Marika.
High Ground is a 2020 Australian film directed by Stephen Maxwell Johnson, based on historical events that
took place in Arnhem Land in the Northern Territory of Australia, set just after World War I.
It has variously been called a revisionist Western and Australian Western.
However, it tells of a true historical event in a fictionalised manner but
with very close attention to and respect for Aboriginal culture.
The film premiered at the 70th Berlin International Film Festival on 23 February 2020,  with the Australian premiere at the
Brisbane International Film Festival later that year, and theatrical release in Australia on 28 January 2021.
The film explores themes of bounty hunter, based on true story,
australian aboriginal, australian outback, 1930s.
The tone is emotional and intense.